Let's talk about the Malon Lam case,
okay?   It
's a super high-profile, super
interesting case.  20 years, what we were talking about,
right?  This person was 15, well,
the kid was 20 years old
and it's a super-insane robbery.
Tell me what happened.  Let's see, the
case of Malon Lam, which we can
elaborate on a bit, right?  I imagine.
Uh, it's a super interesting case, many
people have already posted it on YouTube, there are some
very good videos explaining it, but
we have to go back to what we
were talking about from the beginning of
this conversation, right?  A person
who comes from playing Minecraft, who is involved in
the
world of video games, and who
starts to get involved in communities, of course,
on Discord, on Telegram, where in the end they
start to meet people, they start
to meet people who have a
purpose of taking life as
if they were the
administrators, right?  And so it
all begins by meeting four friends,
okay?  Where Malón begins to see
that the world of cryptocurrencies is an
interesting world, that
games are coming out of the world, also NFTs and all
this, and he begins to get very involved in the
world of cryptocurrencies.  From
here on, cybersecurity communities come in
, but these cybersecurity communities don't
want to do good at all, right?  Ultimately, there's a
large community on Telegram,
especially if we delve a bit into
the TOR Deep Web protocol. Of
course, there are communities where people
talk and share knowledge
that you're obviously going to use for
illegal purposes, right?  That's a
debate we could each have about whether it's
right to share knowledge
with everyone, or not, but anyway,
this person takes that knowledge and
uses it illegally,
and with four friends, okay?
Everyone around 20 years old.
All around 20 years old.  I think the
oldest would be 26 or 27, but they are all
20 years old.  His partner, who has the
alias Vox, and dad, right?  I ca
n't remember their names right now, but
Box is his partner, he's
19 years old, he's the one he's known the
longest, and he's the one who comes up with the whole
fishing strategy that we're going
to explain now, right?  So
these people are
many today, okay?  Let's put the four
main ones, right? That's Malón and his and
his other ringleaders, right?
As I said, they're the Nicks, uh, well,
they're the ones who start doing a
study of which wallets are the biggest
per individual, because obviously there are
companies that have very
large wallets, right?  Binance will have the
main wallet which will have a huge amount of
bitcoins, but they directly look at
the individual wallets that
have the most funds, and we have to keep in
mind that the blockchain is completely
public, right?  And especially in BTC there are
cryptocurrencies like XRP, which
we'll talk about now, there's XRP, Monero, uh,
XRM I think it is, well, it doesn't matter,
Monero, which for example the blockchain
is not so public, it's quite encrypted and
the traceability is much more
complicated, but BTC's is not an
open book.  So, they buy
some databases and you're like, damn,
how much does this database cost?  Nothing,
100 euros.  100 euros from
wallets, because tracking a wallet
isn't that complicated, from the
largest wallets worldwide, uh,
with BTC funds,
individual or general,
I think they were from
individuals, maybe I'm
wrong, and they could also be from
companies, but from what I've been
investigating in this
case, uh, they spoke to more than 2000
people, that is, they tried to scam
more than 2000 people who were
individuals, who had half a million, 1
million, 2 million.  And they bought this database
on
forums in the Deep Web or on
normal forums.
No, forums, in forums that are under the
Thor protocol, which the Thor protocol,
well, I could also
explain it, but people should investigate
a little how it works,
like it gives you access to another internet.
The deep web, so people
understand, is the internet we had
25 or 20 years ago, at the beginning of
the 2090s.
It consists of servers that people have
publicly available where data travels via an
Onion protocol, which is the Thor protocol, which
works by hopping, making hops based on
requests.  In other words, I have an IP address, it
connects me to a server, it gives me another IP address, it
connects me to another server, it gives me another IP address, and
finally I arrive at the website, right?
Then it becomes much more difficult to
track.  It's still possible, okay?  Let it be
clear to everyone that some
people have been caught
using that protocol because, in the end,
the police aren't stupid and the
security forces aren't stupid.  So,
taking that into account,
of course, you can access some
websites that you can't access from Google, you can't
, you can't because they are not
public.  So, normally there are
no search engines on the deep web.  I think there are
people who are already creating some kind of search engine
because they have collected the URLs from the
browser and in the end they create a
search engine.  But you just copy, paste,
copy, paste.  You have to put it
in Thor's URL.  I copy, paste, and they are
strings of punion characters, and that's
where there's a server.  So it's a
person who has taken a laptop at home
, downloaded the
Onion protocol, and uploaded a web page.  And on
that website there's a forum
like the one Silk Road had
many years ago, back in 2009, so in the end
everything works a bit the same, right?  It could
be a marketplace for X or forums where
things are discussed.
Then this person entered a forum
where there were cybercriminals who were
posting databases, as we've been
talking about, that get
hacked, and there were also
some interesting databases, right?
Because you start talking and looking and you
say, "Dude, who publishes a
database of wallets with the most funds?"
Well, I knew it.  So, once they
track this database, they
buy it and start throwing things away, throwing
a lot of things away, right?  Think about it,
people probably know about the
243 million hack that we'll
explain now, but in this case, that's
the end of the story.  It's the
end of the story
a little before the end.
Exact.  Then, these
people started throwing a lot of
people.  In the end they are young kids,
they have a lot of time and for several
years, because this happened several
years ago, they started to attack a lot of
people.
But when you say "shoot him," what
exactly were they doing?
Well, they were trying to use techniques
, okay?  Uh, what is osint? It's a
technique we use mainly
in defense,
although attackers also often
use it to gather as much
public information about you as possible on the internet.  And
well, also if I have private things
like this database, I'll collect it and
try to do everything possible to
scam you, to catch you in a phishing scam, right?
Okay.  So, these
databases contained the wallet and who it belonged to,
the first and last name of the person being
tracked.  Yes. So, once they
have that person, they start
tracking them.  They're trying to steal his
Telegram account, his email account, his
social media accounts, everything.  They conduct a study of
his personal life.  So,
this gentleman, whose name I don't think has been
mentioned, he's anonymous,
worked at a trading fund
in Washington, okay?, which
had closed down, and this person had
a wallet with 4100 bitcoins, 110
bitcoins, if I'm not mistaken, okay?  which
at that time had a value of
243,000,000,
since this person was an elderly person.
What does that indicate?  Well, an
older person is a much simpler target
than you and me, because in the
end they don't have a very, very
high level of self-confidence.  A person who, in the end,
does a really, really good fishing, it has to be said
.  Hey, and this person,
Malón's partner from Box, goes to
Google support.  Then they start
making an approach with
Google support, sending SMS messages, sending
emails.  And of course, when you
think, "Who could be
doing this to me?"  I mean,
nobody can think that I'm being
attacked, right?  Because in the end, it's a
person who hasn't bothered anyone,
who doesn't know anyone, and just because they have
that money, you never think
that by having a cold wallet, someone is
going to know who you are your whole life and
all that.
Of course, you can't imagine that it's been
leaked.
No, you just can't imagine it, and even if you could
, you'd say, "Who's going to
dedicate hours and days of their life to
doing research on me and all that?"  And damn, they're
sending me emails and SMS messages
that could very well be from Google.
So, this person starts
receiving calls from
Google support, he starts receiving calls from the
wallet he had, which was Gemini, and
also from support from both Box and
with, right?  Well, it turns out that the
two boys Malon had started pretending to be
him.  And obviously, I
imagine, I should say this now, there are
17 defendants, that is, there were many
people, many people behind it, it's not
just these four, okay?  I imagine
the procedure they followed was
much more extensive, but
these are the most well-known examples.  Sure, and then
also at a hacking level you can call
someone and Google will appear in the
Exactly.  As we were discussing
before the podcast, the
SMS protocol for telephony
today is incorrectly configured by default
and they are not going to change it.  So,
col spoofing can be done
very easily nowadays.
Clear.  So, this person received an
SMS from Google, right?  He'd probably
received other Google logins too,
right?  It appears in the same
SMS conversation
where you literally had, maybe,
Google verification, and below
that message appeared.  It wasn't a new chat room,
and that can be done.
It's crazy, really, but it can be
done.  That's why you
always have to be extra careful.  And well,
this person is finally under
pressure because they're being told that
their account has been compromised.  And
this is where I think he clearly
suffers from a lack of technical knowledge.  They
make you install IDESK, which for
those who don't know what IDESK is, is a
remote computer control software
like Team Beware, which you're probably
more familiar with.
Yes.
And they told him that
his wallet or his Google account was compromised.
That's what I don't know very well.  I think so
, I think it was both things,
because since they kept attacking him from
one side and the other, I think it was a
combination of both.  Then they
connected, and to top it all off, they
recorded it and
were streaming it on
Discord, I think.  I mean, these kids
were mocking us and
streaming everything.  So, everything, I mean, I
think that video is obviously no longer public
.  Maybe if you search on the
internet you can find out
, but they were
documenting everything.  I mean, they're really stupid, to be
honest.  It should be said.
No, they treat it like a game.   They
took it as a game.  That's what
you said.  I mean, in the end they're just
young kids, they thought they
were the administrators
playing GTA, and that's not the case, right?
So, well
, it's true that it's
quite surprising how one can reach
that level of fishing, isn't it?  And above
all, the ability to manipulate a person
to get so upset, but like I
said, it's an elderly person who doesn't have
technical knowledge and who you keep
bombarding.  Hm.  It can happen, it
can happen.  And in this case it happened, didn't it?
Then they connected via Team
Viware on a cloud where he had the
wallet's private key, he
displayed it on the screen and that was it.  They
took a screenshot,
grabbed this, put the wallet in
an Exodus, transferred the funds to another device, and that was it
.  243 million.   It's
crazy.   That's
crazy! Just imagine the
man's face, the poor man's face, how he must have felt
.  And I'm telling you, man,
why do you have 243 million in Bitcoin?
[laughs] Put them in, put them in others.  I
mean, look, you have to be really rich,
but damn, 243 million.   It
probably wouldn't be the only thing he
had.
No, no, no, but in a wallet,
set it at 50, at 30, I don't know, in just one
.  I'm really surprised, to be
honest.  But well, obviously
there will be people,
but maybe he bought it when it was, I don't
know, maybe half a million or a million.
Total.  Yes.
And it's gone up.
Total, total.  But that's it, but it's
the biggest problem, well, what
people who lack knowledge are guilty of, and in the
end you say, "Dude, who's going to
rob me?"  Well, there it is.
And that's it, they made the
transfer and this is where the
dad comes in, right?, whose name is Papa or
Mon, I think, who is the person who
launders the money, right?  He is one
of the four
ringleaders of the Malón group.  And here
he begins to take those Bitcoin funds and
distribute them across more than 30 exchanges.
Not only that, but by using mixers,
which for those who don't know, a mixer is a
decentralized software that takes
BTC, passes it through Monero, for
example, and sends it back to you in Ethereum, and
directly buying Monero.  Okay?
So, of course, from there
they start distributing all that money, they
send it
all in Monero,
all in Monero and in what I'm
telling you, in
software that launders the
money.
Yes, yes, yes.  But everything ends up
becoming a cartoon.
Everything ends up becoming a cartoon.  And to
other coins like Z Cash, which also
have a similar protocol, a little more,
okay?
Uh, a little more anonymous, in quotes.
Clear.  And these people already think they're
invincible.  That's the problem,
once you've done that, you think, dude,
if I also have knowledge of crypto
, who's going to catch me in
crypto?  I mean, you also think it's
super anonymous, that nobody's like that, well
, there are some really good people and that's where it comes in
.  Let me see it,
this one is key.  This kid.  I'll look for it
.
Yes. Uh, Z Dax or something like that.  Yes, thatch
XBT, this is super-insulting.  Okay, and I'm
also going to say the names so
people can see it too, which will be
Jedy el Serrano, who was Box,
then Virchetal, who was Wih, and
Kuna, el Metal, who was the one from
Account, right?  He's this guy.
Those were the
four founders, uh, or the four
of the group and so on.  And well, this guy
is a crack in crypto, he's also a person
who dedicates himself a bit to
digital forensics, he doesn't leave that
forensics.  Well, I don't know, but the guy was a
crypto specialist and he started
tracking the main wallet because,
of course, the victim had the
main wallet, so from
there, once they give it to you, you can
track a bit where these
transactions go.
Clear.  And there are people within the four
founders and the group in general who
start mixing the clean money
they had in Wallets with the money they
had stolen.  And this is a
monumental screw-up because this guy says, "Okay,
this transaction has arrived at this
wallet which is encrypted, but I'm going to see
if this wallet which is encrypted
has ever received funds from other sources."
And indeed, these people had
bought cryptocurrencies on exchanges and
transferred that money to
cold wallets, which is how the laundered money was transferred; that
is, the
dirty money was there. If it had been
a new wallet, it would have been completely
anonymous, but since they had used that
wallet, they had reused it, and from
there you can start to follow the
trail.  And not to mention, obviously, that
Malón spent €500,000 a night in
nightclubs, bought Ferraris, bought
Lamborghinis, gave Virkins to the
girls he wanted to pick up there, and was
a person who recorded everything,
posted it on social media, I mean, he
wasn't intelligent, but as we
've talked about, he's a 20-year-old kid
who just pulled off one of the
biggest robberies in history, probably €
246 million.   I do
n't know who has stolen more than that, but I
mean, without being very organized groups,
as we will talk about another case now, 246
million from an individual, I think it is
the biggest robbery that will ever happen in
history without any kind of... It's
absolute madness.
I think that in history
no rich person has ever had their house broken into and
246 million stolen.  It's a
huge amount of money, a huge amount of money for
an individual to have, not for a
company, but for an individual it's
a lot.  Yes, yes.
So, of course, they went
crazy.  They went crazy.
They started leaving clues, and this
person we've been talking about was very,
very good and started tracing, he started
tracing until one day they located him in a nightclub
.
Obviously, the FBI, NSA, and CIA got involved,
but it was all thanks to this guy
who posted it.
that he published it in X, exactly what I
failed to mention.  He posted it, and one of the
four of us
who have been talking, Serrano, I think,
posted his face,
uh, uh, when, I mean, he showed his face
when they were doing the live stream.
So, from then on it was also fatal,
I mean, for them it was very screwed up.
So now we'll also give a bit of a
conclusion because it seems that
, well, they've caught the four of them, yes,
but even though these people are in jail,
I'm sure they have a wallet with at
least 50 million.  The funds have
n't been recovered, they've only given him, I
think, well, they gave
the guy back €500,000 or I don't know if it was €5,000
or €500,000 but anyway, they haven't
given him the €246, of course not.
And there is a lot of money that has been
seized, but there is a lot of money that
is still lost, they haven't found it.  And
obviously these people know where they are, they
're not stupid.  They'll have it in wallets,
tracked, on a pen drive, on a ledger, and
buried.
So, well, even though they
went to jail, to this day there are 17
defendants, nine convicted who have
said, moreover, that they did do it
, so the sentence is going to be
reduced and when they get out, well, they're going to be
multimillionaires.  Yeah, that's crazy.
So, in conclusion, even though they did
something that obviously for
me should be severely punished and
all their money should have been confiscated, they're going to get
out with 30 years because if Malón was
19 and most of them were 19, 18, damn it, I do
n't know what their
sentence will be, I haven't seen it, but at
most 15 years.
Let's say they'll come out as 35
millionaires
and that's it.  Clear.
So, in conclusion, they have won.
They won, unfortunately, unfortunately
they won, but it's a
super-insane case and this gentleman who had
that money, well, he's never going to get it back
in his life.
He'll recover some of the money little by little, maybe,
but
yes, yes.  Look, if so, and you don't know why,
then when they come out with all that
money, it's dirty money, you know?
It's money that the police will eventually
track, but you ca
n't buy a house with that
money.
No, no, no, no.  Man, if they
do that Lamborghini thing again, the
vannun will be back
in jail.
But hey, in the end they
can go live in Thailand,
you know?   They
can give it to a distant friend, that
this distant friend has that money and
starts sending it to them little by little,
that is, they can do 1000 things
to launder that money in the end.
Yes, yes.  What can we learn
from this?  Be very careful with fishing, that's for
sure.  The
lesson I learned is that if you, well,
first of all, if you have that kind of money
or have money in a wallet,
diversify it, please.  Have at
least five or ten wallets.  We're
talking about you having, look,
if I had half a million to 1 million, I would
diversify everything in wallets,
at least four, in case
one is compromised, which is
very complicated, but it can happen, at
least that they steal part of it, not
all of it.  Never keep your
wallet's private keys on your
computer.  A safe deposit box is placed in the bank on a piece of
paper and that's it.  And when you're ready to
withdraw it, you go to the bank, to the deposit, you take it out
, boom, and that's it, out.  And above
all, trying to doubt everything, like,
why is
Google calling me so much?  Google isn't going to call you.
T is a company,
the company plus one of the largest companies in
the world.  The support isn't
helping you.  If you get hacked on Google it's incredibly difficult to
recover an account.
Neither Google nor Amazon will ever help you;
absolutely nothing will help you
recover your account. They won't tell you it's been
compromised and
call you, send you a message, and that's it.
So, you have to be a little
suspicious. When I
get something like this, I think, "Okay, I just got
an SMS about an Amazon package with
a link. Okay,
fine, let's take that link,
keep it on my iPhone, and check the URL. It
's not amazon.es, so I'll
delete it. That's it. And if it is
amazon.es, well, you can take that
link and enter it into a website
like VirusTotal to see if it
's legitimate or not. If it says it's legitimate,
still be suspicious. Don't enter your credentials;
go directly to the
website, if you're connected to
your home Wi-Fi. So, there are many
things you can do to prevent anything from happening to you
.
Yes, a good strategy, as
you say, is to check the typical email you get about
anything."  Instead of clicking and entering,
you go in, open another tab, search for
Amazon, for example, and go in yourself,
right? And that's it.
Why give them a link you don't even know
where it comes from? Go in yourself, it's going to be
much safer,
100%.
We've seen one of the cases, or rather, the
case of the biggest crypto theft, uh,
from an individual,
from an individual.
And now we're going to see a theft of even
more money, but in this case not done
by one person, because what's crazy about Malón
is that in the end it's a group.
Exactly. A group of geeks, if you can
call them that, who
did that crazy thing, and then it's
also very cinematic, is
n't it? That they earn all that money in
Miami, right? With cars, I don't know what.
It's
cinematic, it's
curious to see.
They should make a movie.
No, no.
Yes, they will. I think they'll make it on
Netflix or one of those platforms, it's to make
a documentary. At least.
Yes.  Yes.
The video you just watched is an
excerpt from a full podcast. If
you'd like to hear the complete podcast, you can
do so by clicking the link
in the description or
by clicking the item next to
me. If you found
this excerpt interesting, please give it
a like and subscribe to the
channel. I'm Adrián Sa, and I'll see you
next time. M.